

### **Profile**

Dedicated Software Engineer with experience in achieving tangible results and cross-team collaboration. Proactive and excited to partner with like-minded individuals to achieve goals. Reliable and collaborative developer with strengths in generating technical and design requirements that improve performance and accessibility. Hardworking team player with problem-solving, ideas-sharing approach to full stack development. Strong interest and aptitude in programming, tech cooperate world, machine learning and robotics.

## **Employment History**

#### Full Stack Software Developer, Campoprime Labs, Nairobi

OCTOBER 2023 - PRESENT

- Developed a microservices architecture that improved system modularity and reduced dependencies between components
- Developed a RESTful API that connected the application to the company's existing systems, resulting in a huge reduction in data processing time
- Coded backend services using Django.
- Wrote and defined clean codes to achieve functional and sustainable web applications.
- Troubleshot and debugged software to identify and rectify errors, minimising work disruptions and down time.
- Conducted UI tests to achieve cost-effective measures and optimise performance.

### Full Stack Web Developer, Hyddroo Harvest, Nairobi

JULY 2023 - NOVEMBER 2023

- Wrote and defined clean codes to achieve functional and sustainable web applications.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Django framework for backend development.
- Worked on various web development projects with a focus on backend technologies.
- Refined and upgraded existing software to continuously improve performance.
- Kept detailed records of releases and software fixes for optimum traceability.
- Designed and developed software systems using initial brief.
- Employed user-focused approach to identify impracticalities hindering user experience.
- Infused software components and third-party programmes to define accessibility and functionality.
- Conducted UI tests to achieve cost-effective measures and optimise performance.
- Tested software solutions following standardised procedures, collating results to formulate actionable insights.
- Built a secure authentication system and user management functionality that met the company's security and privacy requirements
- Utilized a microservices architecture to separate the application into independent components, improving scalability and reliability
- Developed an API that allowed data to be accessed and manipulated from multiple sources, resulting in increased efficiency and flexibility

#### **Details**

Nairobi

Kenya

+254112685851

kingoriaustin01@gmail.com

#### Links

Github

<u>LinkedIn</u>

**Twitter** 

### Co-founder and Full Stack Web Developer, Sokomotives, Nairobi

AUGUST 2022 - DECEMBER 2023

- Developed a full stack web application from scratch, including back-end services, front-end interface, and database
- Co-founded Sokomotives: Conceptualized and established Sokomotives, an online car dealership platform aimed at facilitating direct sales between owners and buyers, eliminating the need for intermediaries.
- Lead Software Engineer: Spearheaded the development of Sokomotives from ideation to launch, leveraging expertise in PHP for backend development and JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap for frontend. Directed the creation of key features such as online auctions, real-time messaging, and virtual showrooms.
- Created and tested various marketing strategies in the automotive industry.
- Strategic Planning and Leadership: Contributed to strategic decision-making, business goal setting, and growth strategy formulation for Sokomotives.
   Provided leadership and direction to the team, fostering a collaborative and innovative work environment.
- Customer Relationship Management: Built and maintained strong relationships
  with car owners and buyers, ensuring that Sokomotives consistently met their
  needs and expectations. Fostered trust and loyalty among the customer base
  through personalized engagement and exceptional service delivery.
- Team Collaboration and Mentoring: Collaborated effectively with cross-functional teams, guiding and mentoring team members to drive productivity and achieve company objectives. Played a key role in fostering a culture of learning and professional development within the organization.

### Software Developer Intern, Bingwa Afya Hospital, Nairobi

JANUARY 2022 - NOVEMBER 2022

- Assisted in all software development project aspects, such as planning, design and building.
- Learned new skills, testing techniques and troubleshooting best practices.
- Created HTML templates, JavaScript files and CSS for UI module development.
- Coded prototypes of new technologies and features for potential integration into future software.
- Tested code for bugs or technical issues, debugging to fix errors and boost performance.
- Learnt new technologies and systems through extensive research and training to understand software functionality.
- Aided development teams with building and maintaining systems powering devices and networks by testing application features, stability and security.

### **Education**

Diploma In Information And Communication And Technology, The Kaiboi National Polytechnic, Nandi County

FEBRUARY 2021 - DECEMBER 2023

- Member of the AjiraDigital group.
- Diploma in I.C.T Graduate.

#### Certificate of Higher Education, Nyahururu High School

JANUARY 2019

- Member and leader in the Christian Union.
- · Leader of the Whiztech Club.

### References

Skills	
Teamwork	
Leadership	
Software Engineering	
Django (Web Framework	)
React Js	
Web Development	
Software Development	
Python (Programming La	nguage)
PHP (Scripting Language)	,
SQL (Programming Langu	age)
Management	
Robotics	
Machine Learning	
C,C++ Hands-on	
Debugging	
JavaScript (Programming Language)	
Software Systems	
Planning	
Application Programming Interface (API)	,
<b>Languages</b> Swahili	
English	

### **Hobbies**

Participating in hackathons. Open Source Contributions. Fitness and wellness. Learning new technologies. Automotive enthusiast.

## Peter M. King'ori from Bingwa Afya Hospital

peterkingo@yahoo.com | +254710408845

### Isaac Kamau from Hyddroo Capital

izaqkamau@gmail.com | +254 705 544426

# **Courses**

Founder Academy (Entrepreneurship & Startups), ALX Academy

MARCH 2024 - JUNE 2024